# John Hirsch V

PORTFOLIO John Hirsch V | LinkedIn jhirschv | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

Software developer skilled in Python, Java, and JavaScript. Experience in full-stack web development using Spring Boot, Django, and React. Strong communication and goal setting skills honed from several years working as a personal trainer. Pursuing developer roles in a technical environment.

## LANGUAGES | FRAMEWORKS | TOOLS

Java, JavaScript, Python | React, Spring Boot, Django | MySQL, AWS, Tailwind

### **EXPERIENCE**

**BestTech** — Launch Code Capstone Project <a href="https://besttech-frontend.vercel.app/">https://besttech-frontend.vercel.app/</a> July 2024 - Present

- Developed a comprehensive eCommerce application with a fully functioning admin dashboard
- Created a product recommendation machine learning algorithm using Python and Scikit-learn
- Integrated JWT Authentication for secure API requests and user logins
- Utilized Shadon/ui and tailwind to develop a modern user interface
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot, React, MySQL, Tailwind CSS, shadon/ui, AWS, Python, Stripe API

Train.io — Fitness Training App <a href="https://trainio-liart.vercel.app/">https://trainio-liart.vercel.app/</a>

January 2024 - June 2024

- Created a fully functioning fitness app that rivals several mainstream applications
- Implemented an Al-powered workout creator through OpenAl's API
- Integrated a comprehensive workout journal to track users workout weights, reps, videos, and notes
- Features a personal training system where users can share workouts, track clients data, and message
- Tech Stack: Python (Django), React.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, shadon/ui

**Discourse** — Chat Application <a href="https://discourse-chat-app-frontend.vercel.app/">https://discourse-chat-app-frontend.vercel.app/</a> January 2024 - July 2024

- Created a real time chat application, allowing users to signup and chat with friends
- Used Django Channels and WebSockets to manage real time messaging
- Designed an interactive React frontend that is fully mobile responsive
- Tech Stack: Python (Django), React.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind CSS, shadcn/ui

**Cloud Code** — Online Code Execution Project

June 2024 - Present

- Created a web based coding environment that allows users to write code that is executed remotely
- Utilized the Docker SDK to spin up docker containers to execute user submitted code
- Developed a frontend text editor using the Monaco text editor react package
- Tech Stack: Python, Django, Docker, React.js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI

**Social Network** — CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript Project

October 2023 - December 2023

- Developed a social network platform with interactive posts and a follow/follower system
- Utilized Django's ORM to manage user data and interactions with efficient database queries
- Incorporated asynchronous JavaScript API requests for single page application functionality
- Tech Stack: Python (Django), JavaScript, WebSockets

## **EDUCATION**

LaunchCode, Web Development, 2024

Old Dominion University, Bachelor of Science, Exercise Science, 2023